(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-09T20:32:30.474713",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ゴザル☆ゴザレ
Gozaru☆Gozare,
なんでもござれっと
Anything goes, you see!
切り捨てゴメンのマジカル☆ワールド
A mercilessly magical☆world!
魔法の呪文
The magic spell...
マジカル☆ゴザル☆レッツゴー！！
Magical☆Gozaru☆Let's Go!!
朝目が覚めたら 遅刻寸前
When I wake up in the morning, I'm almost late,
お気に入りの草鞋を履いたなら
If I put on my favorite straw sandals,
駆け抜ける街道
Down the highway I'll dash!
Running through the highway,
Notジャキンジャキン Yesマジカルワンド
Not clanging-clanging, yes, a magical wand!
どこから見ても魔法少女なり
No matter where you look, I'm a magical girl,
ひれ伏すものども
bow down, mortals!
私服を着飾る
Dressing up in casual clothes,
悪だいかんずたち
you corrupt officials!
ちょっと可愛い 大分可愛い
A little cute, very cute!
拙者のワンドの錆びになってござる！！
You'll become rust on my wand!!
マジカルワンド切り！！ GOZARU☆GOZARE
Magical wand slash!! Gozaru☆Gozare!
討ち入りでござる マジカルまみれうちをお見舞いするでござる
It's a raid, I'll pay you a magical, covered-in-shots visit!
GOZARU☆GOZARE この世界を守る
Gozaru☆Gozare, protect this world!
完璧に可憐な姿 ご覧あれ
Behold my perfectly lovely form!
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical☆Gozaru!
フリフリヒラヒラ そよ風に舞う裾を
Frilly, fluttering hems dancing in the breeze,
ちょっぴり詰まってキメポーズ
striking a cute, neatly posed stance.
拝めよものども
Worship me, mortals!
ござるランドの うるわしきお姫様
The lovely princess of Gozaru Land,
だけど言えない その正体 秘密こそ至上のテンプレでござる！！
but I can't say my true identity—secrets are the ultimate trope!!
GOZARU☆GOZARE 闇討ちでござる
Gozaru☆Gozare, it's a sneak attack!
魔法少女は負わねど 高高笑いでござる
Magical girls don't lose, laughing proudly, Gozaru!
GOZARU☆GOZARE 魔法の国から お忍びで舞い降りた 謎の転校生
Gozaru☆Gozare, a mysterious transfer student who flew down in disguise from the magical kingdom!
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical☆Gozaru!
そんな風に素敵を作りたい
I want to create wonderful things like that,
いつだって可愛くなりたいと願う
always wishing to become cuter.
忘れちゃいけない魔法を守りたいでござる
I want to protect the magic we must never forget, Gozaru!
GOZARU☆GOZARE いつまでもござる
Gozaru☆Gozare, forever Gozaru!
胸キュンな一撃をお見舞いするでござる
I'll deal you a heart-throbbing blow, Gozaru!
GOZARU☆GOZARE この世界を守る
Gozaru☆Gozare, protect this world!
完璧に可憐な姿 ご覧あれ
Behold my perfectly lovely form!
魔法少女まじかる☆ござる
Magical Girl Magical☆Gozaru!
GOZARU☆GOZARE Let's Go!!
chu chu yeah!
please me!
without you!
あー！ なんてことだ
Ah! Good grief,
些細な過ちだ
such a trivial mistake.
自分のことにタラッタラッタ手焼く
I'm struggling so much with myself.
どうして突然？ 逃げ切ったっていいでしょ？
Why all of a sudden? It's fine to run away, right?
だけどなんだか気まぐれモードになり そんな気分になっちゃって
But somehow, I got into a moody whim and ended up feeling like this.
始まりはそんな風で つまりはらしくないようで
That's how it all started—meaning it's not really like me at all.
でも今じゃ扉開けて ほら 声が聞こえるよさあ！
But even so, open the door now—look, you can hear voices, come on!
行こう！
Let's go!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ！
I have the courage to become your wings!
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
No trial is scary because I have that magic!
初めて出会う世界に花束を贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet of flowers to the world we meet for the first time!
ただこの瞬間結ばれるよ
We are bound together in this very moment.
チクタクなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない 明日から平和なら！
A tick-tock communication is fine, as long as tomorrow is peaceful!
chu chu yeah! please me! chu chu yeah! without you!
どうしてまた素直になれなくて 自分のことでチュルッチュルッチュルッ
Why can't I be honest again? Churu-churu-churu about myself...
ギアはそのままで スピード上げていこう
Let's keep the gear as is and crank up the speed!
だけどなんだか黄昏モードになり
But somehow, entering twilight mode...
いつかを思い出しちゃって
Remembering days gone by...
一人いてでも嫌じゃない
Being alone isn't so bad either,
誰にも頼らなくてもいい
And I don't need to rely on anyone.
でも扉の向こう騒がしい
But beyond the door, it's so noisy—
声が聞きたいよ 今
I want to hear your voice, right now!
行こう！
Let's go!
僕は君の背中に
I'll become your wings,
乗せて空を舞うよ！
And carry you dancing through the sky!
いつか心が離れても
Even if our hearts drift apart someday,
その時は笑ってて
Remember to smile when that time comes.
守りたいこの世界に 青空のラプソディ
In this world I want to protect, it's a blue sky rhapsody.
ただいつまでも奏でててよ
Just keep playing it forever and ever.
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーションでも別に大丈夫さ
Even if our communication is awkward, it's totally fine!
明日はまだ平和だ ほんの小さな傷を
Tomorrow is still peaceful. Just take our smallest scars,
太陽にさらして 分け合ったよ君と
And expose them to the sun—sharing them with you,
痛みは熱さの中に溶けてく！
The pain melts away into the warmth!
chu chu yeah!
息を切らし without you!
Out of breath, without you!
手を叩いて chu chu yeah!
Clap your hands, chu chu yeah!
次なるリズムではしゃぐアリーナ 飛び跳ねてさ
Dancing around the arena to the next rhythm, jumping up and down!
chu chu yeah! please me!
手を叩いて chu chu yeah!
Clap your hands, chu chu yeah!
次なるリズムではしゃぐアリーナ
Dancing around the arena to the next rhythm!
僕は君の翼に
I'll become your wings,
なれる勇気があるよ！
And I have the courage to make it happen!
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
No trial is scary because we have that magic.
君と出会い世界は 花束に溢れた
The world I found you in overflowed with bouquets of flowers,
ただその瞬間結ばれたよ
And in that very moment, we were bound together.
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない
Even if our communication is awkward, it doesn't matter—
明日が平和なら！
As long as tomorrow is peaceful!
chu chu yeah!
please me!
息を切らし without you! chu chu yeah!
Out of breath, without you, chu chu yeah!
というわけで、みなさん、こんばんはでござる！
And with that, everyone, good evening de gozaru!
風真いろは生誕ライブ2024にお越しくださいまして、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for attending Kazama Iroha's Birthday Live 2024!
見てるー？
Are you watching?
はい、ということで、みなさんもうすでにお気づきかと思いますが、本日のハッシュタグはこちらでございます！
Yes, so, as you probably already noticed, today's hashtag is right here!
見てますか？
Are you watching?
はい、「風真いろは生誕ライブ2024」で、今日はたくさんXにつくしょも、感想も、思ったこと全部おたきびまで全部ポストしてください！
Yes, please post a lot on X with "Kazama Iroha Birthday Live 2024" for all your screenshots, impressions, everything you thought!
誕生日おめでとうコメント見てるよ、みんなありがとう！
I'm reading the happy birthday comments, thank you everyone!
はい、というわけで、ここまで2曲続けてお届けさせていただきましたけども、予告通り1曲目は「魔法少女マジカルでござる」をお届けさせていただきました！どうだったかな？
Yes, so, up to this point we've delivered two songs in a row, but as announced, the first song was "Mahou Shoujo Magical de gozaru"! How was it?
実は今回MVを作っていただいたクリエイターさんにもですね、事前にオファーはしていたものの、なんと振り付け結構MV準拠でやらせていただきました！
Actually, for this time, to the creator who made the MV, although I had asked in advance, somehow we got to do the choreography pretty much based on the MV!
はい、ということで、そうなんです、今回のライブテーマは「なりたい自分」ということで、1つ目まず魔法少女でお届けさせていただきました！ステージはこんな感じです、どうぞ！
Yes, so that's right, this live's theme is "The self I want to be", and we first delivered it with the magical girl theme! The stage looks like this, go ahead!
なんだか変なものがありましたね
There was something weird just now.
やっぱ出そうかなって思うんですけど出していいですか?
I was thinking of bringing it out, but is it okay if I do?
では、いいですか?いきますよ?
Well then, is it ready? Here we go?
せーの!
Ready, go!
でてよ! マジカルワンド出てれー!
Come out! Magical wand, come out!
ちょっとごめんみんな、風真いろはの魔法の力強すぎて風真が言い切るまで出たわ。
Sorry everyone, Kazama Iroha's magic power is so strong it came out before I finished speaking.
ちょっとごめんね強すぎちゃって。
Sorry, it was a bit too strong.
と、俺なんかやっちゃいました?
Like, "Did I do something?"
状態なんですけどもマジカルワンドでーす!
That kind of mood, but here's the magical wand!
いいでしょう、MVと同じやつです。いぇーい。
Pretty cool, right? Same as the MV. Yay.
ということは、みんなのあれができますね?
That means everyone can do "that", right?
なんかいもなんかいも練習した、あれを皆さんにやっていただきたいと思うんですけど、皆のよろしいですかー?
I want everyone to do the thing we practiced over and over, is everyone ready?
はーい!
Yes!
え、スタッフの皆さんもよろしいですかー?
Um, are the staff members ready too?
はーいっていう声が今風真いろはの耳元に聞こえております。
I hear a "Yes!" right in Kazama Iroha's ears.
それでは皆さん、いきますよ?
Well then everyone, here we go?
くらえ! マジカルワンド切り!
Take this! Magical wand slash!
はい、今スタッフさんの声も皆さんのコメントも届きました。ありがとうございます!
Yes, I received both the staff's voices and everyone's comments. Thank you!
はい、というわけでこのままでですね、魔法少女パートは続いていくんですけれども、
Yes, so with that, the magical girl part will continue,
次はゲストパートとなります。
but next is the guest part.
今回ですね、風真結構勇気を出していろんなコラボメンたちを誘わせいただきましたので、
This time, Kazama mustered up quite a bit of courage to invite various collab members,
この後もぜひお楽しみにして、次も、えっと、えっとなんだっけ? あ、魔法少女パートでお送りさせていただきます。
so please look forward to the rest! Next, um, what was it? Ah, we'll send it through the magical girl part.
はい、それでは次のパートに行ってみましょう!というわけで次員はゲストパート!
Yes, well then let's go to the next part! So next is the guest part!
レッツゴーでござる! ぶんぶんぶんぶん!
Let's go for de gozaru! Zoom zoom zoom zoom!
MOON PRIDE あなたの力になりたい
MOON PRIDE, we want to be of assistance to you
涙は頬を伝い
Tears streaming down my cheeks
瞳は紅く 燃える
Eyes burning red
稲妻のように 激しく
Violent like a flash of lightning
誰かが 愛を叫ぶ
Somebody cries out for love
例え どんな暗闇でも 一人じゃないよね?
No matter what kind of darkness, we're not alone, are we?
私達を照らす moonlight
The moonlight shines upon us
嘶け 女の子にも 譲れない矜持がある
Ah, girls won't surrender their pride either
それは 王子様 に命運投げず 自ら戦う意志
They won't give up their destiny to a prince, they have the will to fight for themselves
shiny make up 輝くよ 星空を集めて
Shiny make up, sparkling, assemble the starry skies
ただ護られるだけの弱い 存在じゃないわ
We're not just frail weaklings who just need to be protected
哀しみの波に揺られ 怒りの炎に焼かれても
Waves of sorrow shaking us, even if scorched by the fire of anger
稲妻のように眩く 永久の愛を誓う
Dazzling like lightning, swearing eternal love
例え 今は離れていても 一人じゃないよね?
Even if we are apart now, we aren't alone, are we?
私達を繋ぐ moonlight
The moonlight connecting us
嘶け 女の子には 無敵の武器がある
Ah, girls have a weapon of invincibility
それは 弱さに寄り添う眼差すと 全て受け入れる強さ
That is the gaze clinging to weakness and the strength to accept everything
shiny make up 煌くよ 星空に抱かれて
Shiny make up, gleaming, embraced by the starry skies
時空を超えた絆が 私に勇気をくれる
The bond transcending spacetime gives me courage
恋しくて 切なくて 泣きたくなるよ
So in love, so painful, I want to cry
逢いたくて 寂しくて 駆け出しそうなハート
Wanting to see you, feeling lonely, a heart ready to run out
この広い宇宙で 何度生まれ変わっても
In this wide universe, no matter how many times I am reborn
あなたに 恋をする
I will fall in love with you
shiny make up 羽ばたくよ 星空の彼方へ
Shiny make up, spreading wings to the beyond of the starry skies
罪が廻る世界でも 未来を信じられる
Even in a world where sin revolves, I can believe in the future
――だから
--Therefore
shiny make up 戦うよ 星空を纏って
Shiny make up, fighting, wearing the starry skies as a garment
新しい伝説が 今ここから始まる
A new legend begins right here, right now
la la pretty guardian sailor moon
MOON PRIDE
あなたの力になりたい
We want to be your strength
涙は頬を伝い 瞳は赤く 燃える
Tears stream down our cheeks, our eyes burn red
稲妻のように 激しく 誰かが愛を叫ぶ
Someone fiercely cries out for love like lightning
例え どんな闇でも 一人じゃないよね？
No matter what darkness comes, we're not alone, right?
私達を照らす moonlight
The moonlight shines upon us
愛とか恋とか全部くだらない
Love and romance are all worthless
がっかりするだけ
Just getting disappointed
ダメを知るだけ
Knowing what fails
あたし馬鹿ね ダサい逆走じゃん
I'm so stupid, running the wrong way pathetically
ホントのところは あなたにモテたい
The truth is, I want you to like me
失敗するのに ビビってるだけ
Just being too scared to fail
加工なしの 厳しめの条件じゃ
With strict conditions and no filters
ちょっと こんな時 どんな顔すればいいか教えてほしい
Tell me what kind of face I should make at a time like this
ちょっと 「愛してる」だとかそんな言葉で壊れてみたい
I want to break apart with words like "I love you"
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が 怒っちゃってイライラ
So frustrating, my unruly bangs are making me irritated
大好きは もっと可愛くなって 言いたいのに
I want to say "I love you" looking even cuter
だいじょばない ちょっと 蛹になって 出直すわ
It's no good, I'll become a chrysalis and start over
あ…えと、いや…なんでもない
Ah... um, no... it's nothing
言いたいこと 言えたことないや
I've never been able to say what I wanted to say
目と目 止められないの
Eyes can't meet
逸らしちゃって また自己嫌悪
Avoiding and feeling self-loathing again
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 入んないの この靴が 怒っちゃってイライラ
So frustrating, these shoes won't fit, getting irritated
鐘が鳴って 灰になって
The bell rings, turning to ash
あたしまだ 帰りたくないや
I still don't want to go home
××コースへ 飛び込んでみたいから
Because I want to jump into the unknown course
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が 怒っちゃって
So frustrating, my unruly bangs are angry
夜行前のシンデレラ ビビっちゃってフラフラ
Cinderella before nightfall, scared and unsteady
ハローをくれたあなたと 踊っちゃってクラクラ
Dancing and feeling dizzy with you who gave me a hello
大好きは もっと可愛くなって 言いたいのに
I want to say "I love you" looking even cuter
だいじょばない ちょっと お待ちになって 王子様
It's not okay, please wait, Prince Charming
ダメ よ 順序とか もっと仲良くなってそうじゃないの？
No way, what about order? Shouldn't we get closer?
まじ でだいじょばない やっぱ 蛹になって 出直すわ
Seriously not okay, I'll become a chrysalis and start over
止め 止め 止められないの
Can't stop, stop, stop
逸らしちゃって また自己嫌悪
Looking away and feeling self-loathing again
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 入んないの この靴が 怒っちゃってイライラ
So frustrating, these shoes won't fit, getting irritated
鐘が鳴って 灰になって
The bell rings, turning to ash
あたしまだ 帰りたくないや
I still don't want to go home
××コースへ 飛び込んでみたいから
Because I want to jump into the unknown course
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が 怒っちゃってイライラ
So frustrating, my unruly bangs are angry and irritated
夜行前のシンデレラ ビビっちゃってフラフラ
Cinderella before nightfall, scared and unsteady
ハローをくれたあなたと 踊っちゃってクラクラ
Dancing and feeling dizzy with you who gave me a hello
大好きは もっと可愛くなって 言いたいのに
I want to say "I love you" looking even cuter
だいじょばない ちょっと お待ちになって 王子様
It's not okay, please wait, Prince Charming
ダメ よ 順序とか もっと仲良くなってそうじゃないの？
No way, what about order? Shouldn't we get closer?
まじ でだいじょばない やっぱ 蛹になって 出直すわ
Seriously not okay, I'll become a chrysalis and start over
じれったいな ハロー 残念なあたし 困っちゃってイヤイヤ
So frustrating, hello, disappointing me, getting flustered
じれったいな 決まんないの前髪が 怒っちゃってイライラ
So frustrating, my unruly bangs are angry and irritated
夜行前のシンデレラ ビビっちゃってフラフラ
Cinderella before nightfall, scared and unsteady
ハローをくれたあなたと 踊っちゃってクラクラ
Dancing and feeling dizzy with you who gave me a hello
大好きは もっと可愛くなって 言いたいのに
I want to say "I love you" looking even cuter
だいじょばない ちょっと お待ちになって 王子様
It's not okay, please wait, Prince Charming
ダメ よ 順序とか もっと仲良くなってそうじゃないの？
No way, what about order? Shouldn't we get closer?
まじ でだいじょばない やっぱ 蛹になって 出直すわ
Seriously not okay, I'll become a chrysalis and start over
大好きは もっと可愛くなって 言いたいのに
I want to say "I love you" looking even cuter
だいじょばない ちょっと お待ちになって 王子様
It's not okay, please wait, Prince Charming
ダメ よ 順序とか もっと仲良くなってそうじゃないの？
No way, what about order? Shouldn't we get closer?
まじ でだいじょばない やっぱ 蛹になって 出直すわ
Seriously not okay, I'll become a chrysalis and start over
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん
Mirror, mirror, mirror-san
世界で一番 可愛いがるのはやめてよ
Stop loving me the most in the world
棘のような視線迫る 優しいフリした彼女が
Gazing like thorns pressing close, she put on a gentle act
素敵な晩餐もてなした そっと口に含むと
And hosted a wonderful dinner, which I took softly into my mouth
薄れゆく意識の中で 夢を見てる いつものおとぎ話
Dreaming within my fading consciousness, a usual fairy tale
時が止まる
Time stops
お願い kissで目を覚まして欲しいの
Please, wake me up with a kiss
白い棺から連れ出すように
So as to lead me out of the white coffin
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマ的な事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance
祈っても 王子様はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, Prince Charming still hasn't come
消えてしまうその前に…
Before I vanish...
鏡よ 鏡よ 鏡さん ネクタイ任せや頬に挨拶するから
Mirror, mirror, mirror-san, leaving ties to you and greeting your cheeks
妬みを買われてしまった
I bought jealousy
七人の小人はいるけど 助ける素振り、知らんぷりね
The seven dwarfs are here, but they pretend not to help
そっと首を掴まれ
Softly grabbing my neck
一粒の涙さえ拭えず呼吸もままならない
Can't even wipe a single tear, unable to breathe properly
視界失った 消えそうだから
Losing my vision, I'm about to fade away
早くかけて欲しいの 訳は聞かないで答えられない
I want you to come quickly, don't ask why, I can't answer
望まない憎まれは 深い愛の事情
Unwanted hatred is a matter of deep love
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな 途切れてく命の音
Am I going to disappear soon? The sound of life fading away
助ける素振り 知らん振りね
They make no move to help, just feigning ignorance
そっと首を掴まれ
Gently grabbed by the neck...
一粒の
A single drop of...
涙さえも 拭えなくて
...tear, unable to wipe away.
呼吸もままならない 視界失せた
Breathing is impossible, my vision went dark.
消えそうだから 早く駆けつけて欲しいの
Because I feel like I'm disappearing, run over quickly.
訳は聞かないで 答えられない
Don't ask me for the reason, I can't answer.
望まない 憎まれは深い愛の二乗
Unwanted hatred is the square of deep love.
もうすぐでいなくなるのかな
I wonder if I'll be gone soon...
途切れてく 命の音
The sound of fading life...
毒リンゴを食した 少女のように 眠りにつく
Like a girl who ate a poisonous apple, I fall asleep.
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
I want you to wake me up with a kiss, please.
胸の中の声 届きますか
Can the voice in my chest reach you?
階段を上ったらドアを開けるだけで 見つかるよ
If you go up the stairs and just open the door, you'll find me.
ah...
お願いKISSで目を覚まして欲しいの
I want you to wake me up with a kiss, please.
白い棺から連れ出すように
As if taking me out of a white coffin.
突き刺さる憎しみはドラマチックな事情
The piercing hatred is a dramatic circumstance.
祈っても王子様はまだ来ない
Even if I pray, the prince still hasn't come.
消えてしまう
Before I disappear...
その前に...
Before...
はい というわけで、コラボパートから3曲をお届けしてまいりました！
Yes! And with that, we've delivered three songs from the collab part!
そのパートに帰ってきました！みなさんありがとうございますー！
We're back to the solo part! Thank you so much, everyone!
はい、ということで、たくさんの先輩方にゲスト出演していただきまして、先輩たちと一緒に魔法少女のパート、最後のコラボでですね、え、Moonlightをさせていただきました！
We had many senior members make guest appearances, and together with them, for the magical girl part and final collab, we performed "Moonlight"!
もうかっこいい、やっぱ美少女戦士ですからね、やっぱね、女の子の憧れということで、たくさんの方にご協力いただきました、ありがとうございました！でござる！
It's so cool! They're magical girl warriors after all, a girl's dream. Thank you very much, de gozaru!
そして、そのパート移り変わりまして、
And then, transitioning to that part...
成りたい自分、2つ目。そう、お姫様！いや、まさか風真がお姫様なんて言うと思ってなかったみなさんはびっくりかもしれませんでしたが、
My second ideal self. Yes, a princess! You all might be surprised thinking I wouldn't say I'm a princess,
え、心は乙女、やはりお姫様に憧れるというものということで、こちらをやらせていただきました！ちょっとステージ見てみましょう、どん！
but my heart is that of a maiden, so we did this one! Let's take a look at the stage, ta-da!
うわ、なんかお姫様のお城っぽくね？ めっちゃ、すごくない？この
Wow, doesn't it look like a princess's castle? Isn't it amazing?
このなんか、なんて言うのこういうの、プロジェクションマッピングみたいなかっこいいあの技術で、あのやってくださいました！
They used projection mapping or some cool technology like that for us!
あの、素人には全然わからない技術なんですけど、本当にありがとうございます！かぼちゃの馬車もあったりなんてします！はい！
It's a technology I don't understand at all, but thank you! There was even a pumpkin carriage!
というわけで、ちょっといったん水を飲んでいいですか？ちょっと、死ぬかもしれないので、
So, can I take a quick sip of water? Because I might literally die,
あの、お迎えに来ちゃった王子様じゃなくて違うものが、死ぬ死ぬ死ぬ！
um, not a prince coming to pick me up, but something else—I'm gonna die!
戻りました！
I'm back!
あのなんですけども、あの、びっくりすることに、もうすでにXのトレンドが1位みたいです、みなさん！本当にありがとうございます！たくさんポストしてくれて本当にありがとう！
Amazingly, X trends are already number one! Thank you so much for posting so much!
こんなに早くていいのってぐらいびっくりで、本当にありがとうございます！このあとも元気いっぱい歌って踊りますので、最後まで絶対見ていってください！
I'm so surprised it's this fast! I'll keep singing and dancing, so please watch till the end!
はい、そして、やらせていただいた2つの曲、シンデレラと白雪姫のプリンセスは、こちら皆分かった方も多かったと思うんですけれども、
And the two songs, Cinderella and Shiroi Yuki no Princess wa—I think many of you figured it out,
はい、ムーンプライドからのこちらの3曲、なんとショートのカウントダウンで踊ってたダンスでした！
yes, these three songs starting from Moon Pride were the dances from the short countdowns!
3日前がシンデレラで、2日前が白雪姫のプリンセスはで、1日…
3 days ago was Cinderella, 2 days ago was Shiroi Yuki no Princess wa, and 1 day...
マイがムーンプライとでしたー！
That was 'My Grand Moonlight'!
是非ね、配信終わったあとに練習風景も見たいなって方は
If you'd like to see the practice footage
そちらのショートも、見てみてください！
after the stream ends, please check out those Shorts!
いやご、いろはを責めること、一気にがーって責めるとき、
Well, when I blame myself, blaming myself all at once...
おめでとうありがとう！Xのごれんど1えんありがとう見てるよ！
Congratulations, thank you! Thank you for the X trending No. 1, I see you!
ありがとう！たくさん見てくれて本当にありがとうございます！げん届いてます！
Thank you! Thank you so much for watching! It really reaches me!
はい、そしてまたこのあとはゲストパートに行きたいと思います。
Right, and then next, I'd like to move on to the guest part.
何やらXで匂わせがあったとかもう恥ずかしいから、もう恥ずかしいな、もう直前にですね、
There were some hints on X or something... It's so embarrassing, so embarrassing. Right before this,
あの、ご案内をね、いただきまして、「いい？匂わせてもいいかな？いろはちゃん」ってことでご連絡いただいたんですけど、そう、
um, I received a notice saying, 'Is it okay? Can I drop hints, Iroha-chan?' and I was contacted like that, yeah.
あの方がやってきます。このあとのお姫様パートやはり風真いろはのお姫様といえば、
That person is coming. The princess part after this... Speaking of Kazama Iroha's princess,
この方です！どうぞ！
it's this person! Here you go!
風って 鳥って 私より自由かな
Are the breeze and birds more free than I am?
翼がないなら 走ってく 行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるんだよ going on！
I can do it, going on!
想像とは いつも違ってる
It's always different from what I imagined,
なにもかも 完璧とはいかないけど
And everything isn't always perfect, but
心の底に 泉があるの
There is a spring at the bottom of my heart.
どんなに落ち込んでも また透明なもので満たされていく
No matter how depressed I get, I am filled once again with something transparent.
これって これって なんていう気持ちなの
What kind of feeling is this, what is this?
熱くて痛くて くすぐったくて 涙が出そう
It's hot, painful, tickling, and makes me want to cry.
風って 鳥って 私より自由かな
Are the breeze and birds more free than I am?
翼がないなら 走ってく 行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるんだよ going on！
I can do it, going on!
他の子にあって 私にないもの
Things other girls have that I don't,
分かっているけど つつい比べちゃうよ
I know, but I end up comparing myself anyway.
答え合わせは もうしたくない
I don't want to check answers anymore.
みんなと同じじゃなくても 私にできること 見つけたいの
Even if I'm not the same as everyone, I want to find what I can do.
夢って 愛って 本当はよく知らない
I don't really know what dreams or love truly are.
どんな色 どんな形 どこからやってくるの
What color, what shape, where do they come from?
祈って 願って それだけじゃ叶わない
Praying and wishing alone won't make them come true.
自信がなくても 始めるんだ いつかじゃなくて今 できるよね
Even without confidence, I'll start now, not someday. I can do it right now, right?
going on！
going on!
泉がここにあるの 私をつかさどる源が
The spring is right here, the source that governs me
何があっても枯れたりしない 諦めたつもりでもまた
No matter what happens, it never dries up. Even when I think I've given up,
透明なもので満たされていく これって これって なんていう気持ちなの
I am filled once again with something transparent. What kind of feeling is this, what is this?
熱くて痛くてくすぐったくて涙が出そう
It's hot, painful, tickling, and makes me want to cry.
風って鳥って私より自由かな
Are the breeze and birds more free than I am?
翼がないなら走ってく行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるんだよ going on！
I can do it, going on!
風って鳥って私より自由かな
Are the breeze and birds more free than I am?
翼がないなら走ってく行きたいところまで
If I don't have wings, I'll run to wherever I want to go.
できるんだよ going on！
I can do it, going on!
going on！
going on!
いつか僕らの上をスレスレに
It's strange how I remember
通り過ぎていったあの飛行機を
The airplane that flew just above us
不思議なくらいに覚えてる
So vividly, for no reason at all.
意味もないのに なぜか
On the night I cried out of sheer uselessness,
不甲斐なくて泣いた日の夜に
I simply wished to become stronger,
ただ強くなりたいと願っていた
And searched for the courage required for that.
そのために必要な勇気を
Even if a cruel fate is predetermined,
探し求めていた
Even if it appears before me one day,
残酷な運命が決まっているとして
If I can breathe for just a moment, just this moment,
それがいつの日か僕の前に現れるとして
My heart felt that nothing else mattered.
ただ一瞬 この一瞬 息ができるなら
Someone inside me sings,
どうでもいいと思えた その心を
"Go further away, go further away,"
もう一度 遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと
With an uncontrollable, passionate fervor.
僕の中で誰かが歌う
So that you, with your eyes always swollen from crying,
どうしようもないほど烈烈に
Will never have to be sad again and can smile—
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
This is a song to become a hero like that.
悲しまないように笑える
Farewell, raise your peace sign,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
To the rolling story.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
I knew you weren't weak enough
転がっていくストーリーを
For me to say "I want to protect you."
君が弱くはないのはわかってた
If anything, I was the weak one,
それ以上に僕は弱くてさ
And you were so precious to me.
君が大事だったんだ
Since that day I shouted out loud,
「独りで生きていくんだ」なんてさ
"I'm going to live on my own,"
口をつけて叫んだあの日から
You can laugh at me as I change.
変わっていく僕を笑えばいい
Kick me, bite me, when I'm so afraid of being alone
独りが怖い目を
That I can't even breathe,
蹴飛ばして噛み付いて息もできなくて
And the inside of my buzzing head becomes a mess—
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
To the point where all pretension vanishes,
体裁も外聞も消えてしまうくらいに
Right now, I want to touch your heart.
今は触っていたいんだ 君の心に
Someday, we will surely reach even the distant sun,
僕たちは きっといつか遠く離れた
Get our hands on the dawn, and laugh.
太陽にすら手が届いて
Dyed in a blue-burning color,
夜明け前を手に入れて笑おう
We should be able to run hand in hand
そうやって青く燃える色に染まり
Toward the hazy other side of the town,
おぼろげな街の向こうへ
Stealing and drawing the future with you
手を繋いで走っていけるはずなんだ
In a straightforward story.
君と未来を盗み描き出す
The rough days covered in scabs,
捩りのないストーリーを
The present worn down and frayed,
ガサガサばかり荒れ果てた日々が
Revive through your words,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
Vividly appearing before us.
君の言葉で蘇る
The soul sleeping as a chrysalis,
鮮やかにも 現れていく
That dream abandoned half-eaten—
蛹のままで眠る魂を
Retrieve them once more.
食べかけのまま捨てたあの夢を
Someone inside me sings,
もう一度取り戻せ
"Go further away, go further away,"
もう一度 遠くへ行け 遠くへ行けと
Once more, with an uncontrollable fervor.
僕の中で誰かが歌う
So that you can smile and never be sad again—
どうしようもないほど烈烈に
This is a song to become a hero like that.
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
Farewell, raise your peace sign,
悲しまないように笑える
To the rolling story.
そんなヒーローになるための歌
I knew you weren't weak enough...
さらば掲げろピースサイン
To the rolling story.
転がっていくストーリーを
With no time to even breathe,
息絶えだして噛みついて息もできなくて
My head and stomach became a mess.
騒ぐ頭と腹の奥がぐしゃぐしゃになったって
So that you can smile again,
いつだって目を腫らした君が二度と
This is a song to become a hero like that.
悲しまないように笑える
Farewell, raise your peace sign,
そんなヒーローになるための歌
To the rolling story.
さらば掲げろピースサイン
Stealing and drawing the future with you
転がっていくストーリーを
In a straightforward story.
君と未来を盗み描き出す
The rough days covered in scabs,
捩りのないストーリーを
The present worn down and frayed,
かすぶただらけ荒れ果てた日々が
Revive through your words,
削り削られ擦り切れた今が
Vividly appearing before us.
君の言葉で蘇る
Retrieve those dreams once more.
鮮やかにも現れていく
Go further away, go further away.
鎖のままで眠る魂を
Farewell, raise your peace sign!
かじかんでまで繋いだその夢を
To the rolling story.
もう一度取り戻せ
Once more, retrieve that dream.
遥か天空(そら)響いている祈りは奇跡に
Echoing in the distant skies, prayers become miracles.
黒天(まよなか)の蒼に溶けて流れていく涙の粒
My flowing teardrops dissolve into the blue midnight.
迷いなく包み込む温もりに出会った
Without questions, I was enveloped in your warm embrace.
遥か天空 響いている 祈りは奇跡に
Echoing in the distant skies, prayers become miracles.
真夜中の蒼に 溶けて流れてく涙の粒
My flowing teardrops dissolve into the blue midnight.
迷いなく 包み込む 温もりに 出会った
Without questions, I was enveloped in your warm embrace.
真っ白な雪のように どこまでも素直なコトバ
As pure as snow, your honest, everyday words,
鉄の羽纏った 僕を動かしていく
Set me free from the bindings of my steel wings.
傷つくたびに
The more I'm hurt,
優しくなれる
the kinder I'll become,
君のその 笑顔だけ
wanting to protect your smile alone.
守り抜きたい 願いはひとつ
That is my one wish.
時を越え 刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Transcending time itself is a feeling of sorrow.
まっすぐに 受け止める 君は光の天使
Grasping it straight on, you are an angel of light.
あの日 胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame you lit in my heart that day,
深い闇 解き放って 自由の扉 開いてく
It released me from the darkness and opened freedom's door.
強く果てない 未来へ
I boldly step into the endless future.
冷たい緑の月に 映し出すココロの影
The cool green moon projects the shadow of my heart.
寂しげに つぶやいた
Murmuring lonesomely,
「君のそばにいたい」
"I want to be by your side."
真実と向き合うこと 教えてくれた勇気は
You gave me the courage to face the truth instead of running away.
僕を駆け巡って 希望に目覚めていく
I'm awakening from my dream.
触れ合う気持ち 離れないように しっかりと抱きしめて
The feeling of contact, never wanting to part; embracing each other tightly.
確かな想い 貫いていく
This certainty of emotions penetrates.
銀の海に隠した 空白のページ
Hidden in the silver sea is a blank page.
君だけが知っている 「本当」を僕に見せて
Only you know it, show me the "truth".
吹き荒れる切なさに 生まれていく誓い
The rage and sorrow born of my oath.
もう何も恐くはないよ 結んだ視線そらさずに
No longer afraid of anything, I fix my unwavering gaze.
大切な 「今」 始める
The treasured "now" is beginning.
永遠の炎
The eternal flame...
君が君でいられる場所
The place where you can be yourself,
幻にさらされないように
undisturbed by nightmares and visions,
消えない雨の苦しみも 鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
And the pain of neverending rain. Breaking the key, throwing it away.
隣にいるから すべてを信じて
It's in the next door. Believing in everything.
時を越え 刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
Transcending time itself is a feeling of sorrow.
まっすぐに 受け止める 君は光の天使
Grasping it straight on, you are an angel of light.
あの日 胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame you lit in my heart that day,
深い闇 解き放って 自由の扉 開いてく
It released me from the darkness and opened freedom's door.
強く果てない 未来へ
I boldly step into the endless future.
そう、きっと ここから始まる…
Yes, it starts right here...
まるで御伽の話 終わり
Like a fairy tale ending...
まるで御伽の話
It's like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
Proof that the end has come
長過ぎる旅路から 切り出した一節
A fragment carved from a journey far too long
それはかつてこの地に 影を落とした悪を
The evil that once cast its shadow over this land
討ち取り勇者との 短い旅の記憶
And the memories of a brief journey with the hero who defeated it
物語は終わり 勇者は眠りにつく
The story ends, and the hero falls into slumber
穏やかな日常を この地に残して
Leaving a peaceful everyday life behind in this land
時の流れは無情に 人を忘れさせる そこに生えた軌跡も 錆び付いていく
The flow of time mercilessly makes people forget; even the footprints left there rust away
それでも君の 言葉も願いも勇気も 今も確かに 私の中で生きている
Yet your words, wishes, and courage still live on firmly inside me
同じ道を選んだ それだけだったはずなのに
We chose the same path, or so it should have been
いつの間にかどうして 頬を伝う涙の理由をもっと
Why is it that before I knew it, I wanted to know the reason for the tears streaming down my cheeks even more?
知りたいんだ 今更だって共に歩んだ旅路を辿れば そこに居なくとも きっと見つけられる
I want to find out; if I retrace the journey we walked together, even if you're no longer there, I'm sure I'll find it
物語は続く 一人の旅へと発つ
The story continues, setting off on a solo journey
立ち寄る街で出会う 人の記憶の中に残る君は
You remain within the memories of people met in towns along the way
相変わらずお人好しで 格好つけてばかりだね あちらこちらに作ったシンボルは 勝ち取った平和の証
You're as good-natured and show-offy as ever; the symbols scattered here and there are proof of the peace we won
それすら未来でいつか 私が一人にならないように あの旅を思い出せるように 残された目印
And yet, even those are markers left behind so that someday in the future, I won't be alone and can remember that journey
まるで御伽の話
It's like a fairy tale
終わり迎えた証
Proof that the end has come
私を変えた出会い 百分の一の旅路
An encounter that changed me, a hundred-to-one journey
君の勇気をいつか風がさらって 誰の記憶から消えてしまっても 私が未来に連れて行くから 君の手を取った
Even if the wind someday sweeps away your courage and it fades from everyone's memory, I will carry it into the future, for I took your hand
あの日全て始まった くだらなくて思わずふっと笑ってしまうような
It all started that day, something so trivial it makes me let out a chuckle
ありふれた時間が 今も眩しい
That ordinary time is still so dazzling
知りたいんだ 今更だって振り返るとそこにはいつでも 優しく微笑みかける 君がいるから
I want to know; even now, when I look back, you are always there, smiling gently
新たな旅の始まりは 君が守り抜いたこの地に 芽吹いた命と共に
The beginning of a new journey, together with the life that sprouted in this land you protected to the end
はいというわけで、みんなのたくさん続けて、あの見ていただきました！
Yes, so with everyone continuing so much, um, you watched it!
ゲットスタアと1曲目、えっとプリンセスパートのあづきちゃん一緒にクリア！
Cleared the first song 'Get Star', um, Princess Part with Azuki-chan together!
そして今回またステージ変わりまして、
And this time the stage has changed again,
こちら次のなりたい自分、ヒーローということで、ヒーローテーマでやらせていただきました！
we did this with the theme of the next 'ideal self', a hero!
ピースサイン王冠先パイと、そして必ずブレイザーですね、王冠先パイとあづきちゃんと3人でやらせていただきました！
We did it with three people: Peace Sign Oukan Senpai, and Blazer-san, along with Azuki-chan!
いかがだったでしょうか、めちゃくちゃかっこよかった、かっこよかった、ヒーローはね、
How was it? It was super cool, so cool, heroes are,
そうだよ、風真の色はかっこいいんだよってこと、みんなに知ってもらえて、嬉しいですね、ありがとうございます！
that's right, I'm glad everyone got to know that Kazama Iroha is cool, thank you!
はい、実はですね、あの今回の皆のお気づきかと思うんですけども、
Yes, actually, I think everyone might have noticed this time,
3Dの、あの1番最初、えっと1周年の時ぶりにですね、あの呼びした、あのあづきちゃんとフォークス以外にお呼びしたあづきちゃんと、あとカント先輩に今回はそれぞれまた1曲ずつお願いして、で最後は3人で
for the 3D, since the very first 1st anniversary, we invited Azuki-chan and... besides Folks, we invited Azuki-chan and Kanto Senpai to each do one song this time, and finally the three of us
やりたいなっていうことでお願いさせていただきました！
asked to do it together!
本当にありがとうございました！先輩方本当にありがとうございました！めちゃくちゃ楽しかったです！
Thank you truly so much! Senpai, thank you so much! It was super fun!
はい、やっぱりですね、なりたい自分今回そしてヒーローで、あのコラボパートから始まったんですけども、やっぱり、道を踏み歩いていこうということで、憧れるヒーロー、やはり勇者が一番合いますね！
Yes, after all, starting from the collaboration part with 'ideal self' and 'hero' this time, walking along the path, the hero we admire most is definitely the hero!
めちゃくちゃ難しかったんですけど、死ぬほど練習して、あの歌えるようにまりました！息継ぎとかね、めちゃくちゃ大変だったんですけど、細かくね、そうやってボイトレの先生に教えていただいて、
It was super difficult, but I practiced to death and became able to sing it! Breath control and such were super tough, but being taught in detail by my vocal trainer,
たりとかして 歌いりょうのった 勇者 それを段差付きで頑張らせていただきました!
Thank you all so much! Your singing was amazing,
いただきました! めっちゃみんながかっこよかったっていうぷれらのうれしすぎて今もう半分涙途切れてる
and everyone's coolness made me tear up halfway through.
んだけど今もう半分涙途切れてるんだよねけど本当にありがとうございます!
I'm crying tears of joy!
ふりすごかった! かっこよかった! 歌もすごかった! ありがとうございます!
Your performance was amazing, and you looked so cool!
歌もすごかった! ありがとうございます!
Thank you so much for the wonderful songs!
はい、ちょっとね、まだまだみんなとのと一緒に喜びを噛み締めていきたいところなんですけれども、
I'd love to savor this joy with everyone a bit more,
やっぱみんなも待っているかなと思って、そろそろ告知しないといけないかなって思って、
but I know you've all been waiting, so I should probably make the announcement soon!
聞きたいよね? のの、聞きたいよね?
You want to hear it, right?
というわけで、少し休憩かつ告知タイムをさせていただければと思いますので、お付き合いください。
So without further ado, let's get into the announcement and break!
お付き合いください。
Please bear with me!
それではまず1つめの告知、それではいきます、どどん!
Here is the first announcement! Tada!
はい、今年も出ます風真いろは誕生日記念グッズ
Yes, this year as well,
2024年販売決定しました! イエイ!
the Kazama Iroha Birthday Celebration 2024 merchandise is officially confirmed for release! Yay!
めちゃくちゃ可愛いらしいですね。今回はマジカルゴザルなんとグッズになりますので、
It's a super cute line-up! This time, it's actually merchandise featuring Majical Gozaru,
のみなのと、最後までラインナップ見てってくださいね。
so please check out the lineup to the very end!
それでは詳細を見ていきましょう。
Let's check out the details!
まずはこちら!
First up is this!
はい、マジカルゴザルTシャツ!
The Majical Gozaru T-shirt!
なんとみんな大好きゴザルさんを胸元にあしらった素敵なTシャツでございます。こちら、あの、描かせていただきました。
It's a wonderful T-shirt featuring everyone's favorite Majical Gozaru right on the chest, which I got to design.
そして背中には、ええと、コンセプトのイラストになっている、こちらマジカルゴザルのイラストを、
And on the back is the concept illustration of Majical Gozaru!
みなさん全力にお願いいたしますと、ありがとうございます! 本当にめちゃくちゃ可愛い!
I'd really love for everyone to get one!
ありがとうございます! ぜひ、みなのに来てもらえたら嬉しいなと思っております。
I'd be so happy if you could wear it to my events!
そして、あの、今後ね、あの、風真いろはの生誕祭とかやるときのスタッフさんはね、みんなこれ着用が義務付けられてますので、見る側の皆さんもこれ着用義務なので、よろしくお願いしまーす。
And for all the staff working at my birthday stream and future events, wearing this is basically mandatory!
全員来てくださいね。よろしくお願いしまーす。
Please all get one!
はい、天井もらいました。
Yeah, I got permission!
じゃあ、それでは次、こちら!
Now, let's look at the next item!
はい、マジカルゴザルフォンタブ!
The Majical Gozaru Phone Tab!
スペースで話したときに、みんな知らないって言われたのがすごく多くて、えっ、意外! と思ったんですけど、
When I talked about it on stream, so many people said they didn't know about it, which surprised me a bit!
はい、こちらフォンタブでございます。クリアケースに挟んで、あの、充電ケーブルさすところから出して、で、ストラップをつけて首から下げる、みなのと、の、え、スマホをお守りします。安全第一のフォンタブとなっております。
So, this is a phone tab! You put it in a clear case, thread the charging cable through, attach the strap, and hang it around your neck to protect your smartphone.
ぜひね、みなののイベントとかね、スマホパッて出せたほうが便利だと思うので、ぜひね使ってもらえたら嬉しいです。
It's super convenient for events or just pulling out your phone, so I hope you'll use it!
はい、そして次、めちゃくちゃ喜びをみんな、こちら!
And now for the next item everyone's been waiting for, this!
はい、ポコベニなりきり! いろはぬいぐるみ!
The Pokobee-turned-Iroha Plushie Mascot!
というわけで、いやあ、言ってたね、みんな。
So, yeah, like I've been saying,
ポコベのね、なんかいろいろなったファンアートとか見ていて思いついたんですけど、
seeing all the fan art of Pokobee made me come up with this idea.
これはポコベがいろはになっているのか、いろはがポコベになっているのか、正直よく分かりません。
Is Pokobee turning into Iroha, or Iroha turning into Pokobee? I honestly can't tell!
はい。ではなく、今回風真いろはがポコベになりきってコスプレした特別なぬいぐるみになっております。
Well, this is a special plushie where Kazama Iroha has dressed up as Pokobee!
はい。このポコベのもふもふ感と、ゴザルのね、このなんとも言えない、えっさ顔を一緒に和お楽しみください。
You can enjoy both Pokobee's fluffy feel and Gozaru's sassy face together!
はい、なんとカラビナ付いてますので、ぜひみなののも連れて歩いてもらえると嬉しいです。
It even comes with a carabiner, so I'd love for you to take it on walks with you!
こちらはデザイン鮫あんこ先生に
Designed by Sameanko-sensei!
お願いさせていただきました! ぜひみなのとたくさんゲットしてね。
Be sure to get yours!
はい、そして次がこちら。ゴザルさん付きバケットハット!
Next is this, the Gozaru-san bucket hat!
ということで、いや、ちょっとね、やっぱブランド化っていうのを目指していこうと思って、やっぱいろんななりたい自分がいるけど、やっぱみんながさ、ブランド化を望んでくれたらなれるんじゃないかと思って今回作らせていただきました。
I wanted to make something branded because, you know, while I have lots of things I want to become, I thought if people wanted branded goods, it might actually happen!
はい。こちらですね、Tシャツとセットで着ていただくと、なんと全身
And if you wear this with the T-shirt,
ゴザルさんコーデができちゃうという代物になっておりますので、
you can achieve a complete Gozaru-san look!
これを機にぜひみなのとゲットしてくださいね。
So please definitely get one!
よろしくお願いします!
Thank you!
はい、そして次こちらが、ええと一応紹介しますか。
And next, let me introduce this one.
じゃあ、こちらお願いします。ええと、マジカルゴザルの元気のでる魔法
The situation voice pack,
ええ、シチュエーションボイスとなっております。
"Majical Gozaru's Energizing Magic"!
元気のない方におすすめで、今回も頑張ってボイスなどを撮らせていただいておりますが、聞く聞かないは皆様のご自由でございますので、あの、そっと聞いていただけると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします。
It's recommended if you're feeling down, so please give it a listen!
はいじゃあ次行こうか。はい次次次次、はい、フルセットはこんな感じになってます。全部可愛いでしょう!
And here is the complete set! Everything is so cute!
そして、今回もあります。ええと、フルセット、今回もあります。購入特典がこちら!
And we also have a purchase bonus for the full set!
はい、数量限定直筆サインあります。
It's usually quantity-limited,
でも今回はめっちゃお早めにしたから許して。本当ににお早めにしたの。この後22時からもオープンなので、数量限定なんですけど、直筆サインは本当にめっちゃ頑張って増やしたので許してください。
but this time I made it available for a generous 22-hour open period, so please forgive me for making it time-limited!
お願いします。
Please!
そして、ええと、数量限定に関係なくフルセットご購入いただいた方にはASMRのボイスがついてくるんだって。
And regardless of the quantity limit, anyone who purchases the full set will also get a bonus ASMR voice!
ASMRってなんだっけ?
ASMR... what was that again?
記憶が遠くなっていくな。
My memory is getting a bit fuzzy,
でも、確か一緒に誕生日をすごく
but I'm pretty sure we spent my birthday together...
シチュエーションをとった気がする。
I feel like I've got the situation down.
あ、今日緊張っていう言葉を捨ててきたんでね、
Ah, I left the word "nervous" behind today, so
あのこれ以上は行けないということでぜひ興味のある方はフルセットを購入して聞いてみてください。
well, since we can't go any further, please purchase the full set if you're interested and give it a listen.
はい、そして、えっと変わらずこのあとですね、ライブが長引く可能性ありますが、
Yes, and as always, after this, there's a chance the live might run long, but
カートオープンは22時まで。みんなちょっとライブ見ながら、あの戦ってもらえると嬉しいです。すみません、よろしくお願いします。
the cart will be open until 22:00. I'd be glad if everyone could watch the live while managing. Sorry, and thank you!
そして、次の告知です。
And here is the next announcement.
この後22時15分からメンバーシップ限定でアンコールライブを開催いたします。
Starting at 22:15 after this, we will hold an encore live exclusive to members.
今までみんなの前でやったことなかったぼっちなんちゃらとかぼっちなんちゃらとかぼっちなんちゃらをなんと今回ですね、あの音楽ライブです、やらせていただきますので、
Songs like "Bocchi" that we've never performed in front of everyone before, we will actually perform as a music live this time,
ぜひまだまだござるの歌やダンスが聴きたい見たいぞって方はねメンバーシップ入ってみてもらえると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
so if you still want to hear and see Gosaru's singing and dancing, I'd be happy if you joined membership. Thank you!
そして、みんなのと、大切な告知があともう1つあるんですけど、
And, there's one more important announcement for everyone, but...
風は凪いでようだな。そして和が来る、ござる来るまでに、1/3、2/3と刻んでまいりました。
The wind has calmed down. And until harmony/Gosaru arrives, we've ticked off 1/3 and 2/3.
それでは、3/3を告知させていただきます。それがこちら、ドドン！
Now, let's announce 3/3. That is this, ta-da!
この後24時からリリース、ええと風真いろは4曲目のオリジナル曲「Dreamy Sky」をリリースさせていただくことになりました！やったー！
Starting at 24:00 tonight, Kazama Iroha's 4th original song "Dreamy Sky" will be released! Yay!
そして22時5分からライブが終わったあと、5分10分かちょっとあのライブの終了時間にもよるんですけども、プレミア公開がええと、お待ち受けておりますのでぜひみんなあのね、このあとプレミア公開見に行ってください！
And after the live ends at 22:05, depending slightly on the end time, around 5 to 10 minutes later, a premiere screening awaits us, so please everyone go check out the premiere!
素敵な曲はpiccoさんが作ってくださいました。キラキラ、ふわふわな可愛い曲です。よろしくお願いします！
picco-san kindly created this wonderful song. It's a sparkling, fluffy, cute song. Please check it out!
そしてこちらなんですけども、この後のパートで、ええダンスをですね、初披露させていただきまして、歌も初披露させていただきまして、えっと、何て言ったらいいんだろな、N分の後ろでちょっとね流しちゃったりなんかするんですけども、
And as for this part, in the following part, we will perform the dance and vocals for the very first time... um, how should I put it, we might play it in the background or something, but-
あのダンスをですね、今日実はあの近くにいつもダンス、お世話になってる先生が来てくださってるんですけど、なんと結構共作で、共同制作でですね、一生懸命作らせていただいた振り付けなので、ぜひいろんな方に踊っていただけると嬉しいなと思っておりますので、
actually, the dance teacher who always takes care of us came nearby today, and we worked really hard on this choreography together as a co-production, so I'd be so happy if lots of people could dance to it.
よろしくお願いします！ダンスもよかったら注目してみてください。最後まで応援よろしくお願いします！
Please look forward to it! If you'd like, please pay attention to the dance as well. Thank you for your support until the end!
その前に、お水を飲んできてよろしいでしょうか？お水飲ませてください、本当に！お水、お水！
Before that, may I go drink some water? Please let me drink some water, really! Water, water!
お水飲まないと死んじゃうよ。
If I don't drink water, I'll die.
ああ、それにしてもお水が、お水が、お水が、お水が、お水が。ちょっと待って、みんなちょっと1杯飲まないと死ぬかもしれない。
Ah, still, water, water, water, water, water. Wait a minute, everyone, if I don't drink a glass I might die.
はい、お待たせしました。すいません、皆さんあのちょっと一応ね、スタッフさんに「もう一度いっとけ」って言われたんで、ほぼ確定で22時ちょっと押しちゃうそうなので、申し訳ないです本当に。
Yes, sorry to keep you waiting. The staff told me "say it one more time", so it's almost certain it will push past 22:00 a bit, so I'm really sorry.
あのカート、皆さんちょっと準備万端にしといてください。よろしくお願いします。グッズのカート準備万端にしといてください。よろしくお願いします。
Everyone, please make sure your cart is fully prepared. Thank you. Please have your merch cart fully ready. Thank you.
はい、それではお待たせいたしました！ええ、ここで新しいオリジナル曲「Dreamy Sky」を初披露させていただきます。それでは聞いてください。風真いろは4曲目オリジナルソング、「Dreamy Sky」！
Yes, thank you for waiting! Um, here we will premiere our new original song "Dreamy Sky". Please listen. Kazama Iroha's 4th original song, "Dreamy Sky"!
Let's go! ときめいた青空で
Let's go! In a sparkling blue sky,
もっと風に乗りきらめくの Dreamy
glittering even more on the wind, Dreamy
今より可愛くなりたい
I want to be cuter than now,
キュンとね想いこんなんでもバキュンだ!
with a throbbing feeling like this, it's a direct hit!
まぶたに映る方位星
The guiding star reflected on my eyelids,
夜空の中飛び込んだ Shiny Girl
A Shiny Girl who leapt into the night sky,
手が届きそうなほど近く
So close it feels like my hands can reach it,
三日月拝んで、町の明かりを数えたら
Worshipping the crescent moon, and counting the town's lights,
眠りに就く枕元の Secret Girl
A Secret Girl falling asleep by her pillow,
まだ見つからない夢探しに行こう
Let's go search for a dream we haven't found yet.
雨の日でも 晴れの日でも
Even on rainy days, even on sunny days,
まっすぐに咲いてる花のように
Like a flower blooming straight and true,
いつだって ずっと どこだって そっと
Always forever, everywhere gently,
輝く魔法を Let's go!
Shining magic, Let's go!
Let's go! ときめいた青空で
Let's go! In a sparkling blue sky,
もっと風に乗りきらめくの Dreaming
glittering even more on the wind, Dreaming
今より可愛くなりたい
I want to be cuter than now,
キュンとね想いこんなんでもバキュンだ!
with a throbbing feeling like this, it's a direct hit!
華やかなドレス身に纏い
Wearing a gorgeous dress,
誰かを待つ憧れの princess girl
waiting for someone, an adored princess girl.
あーなりたい理想と比べてばっか
Ah, always comparing myself to the ideal I want to be.
道に迷って1人悩んで
Getting lost on the path and worrying alone,
挫れそうになっても大丈夫！
even if I feel like giving up, it's alright!
君と出会って笑顔になって
Meeting you and breaking into a smile,
輝く魔法 Let's Go!
shining magic, Let's Go!
ありふれた日常も
Even ordinary everyday life
もっと風吹いて動き出す jumping
starts moving more as the wind blows, jumping.
飛び立つ希望を探して
Searching for hope to take flight,
弾ける想いは何度でもバッキュンだ！
my bursting feelings hit you with a "bakkyun!" every time!
助けられるだけじゃない
It's not just about being helped,
私も守りたい
I want to protect as well.
そう！ずっと思い描いた
Yes! Connecting the days
日々を繋いで重なるいろは
I always envisioned, our colors overlap.
やっと気づいた本当の願い
Finally realizing my true wish,
なんてちょっぴりお大げさだけどどうかな
though it's a bit of an exaggeration, I wonder how it sounds.
この時間がいつまでも続きますように
May this time last forever,
君と今 Let's Go!
with you now, Let's Go!
ときめいた青空で
In the throbbing blue sky,
もっと風に乗りきらめくの dreaming
riding the wind more and sparkling, dreaming.
今より可愛くなりたい
I want to become cuter than now,
キュートな想いは何度でもバッキュンだ！
cute feelings hitting you with a "bakkyun!" no matter how many times!
みなさん、このライブも最後の曲になりました。今回は3回目の誕生日なので
Everyone, this live has reached its final song. Since this is my 3rd birthday,
「愛言葉III」を歌って終わりにします。
I'll sing "Aikotoba III" to wrap it up.
今日は本当に来てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for coming today!
想いの冒険を 忘れずに全部言えるかな
Can I recount the adventure of my feelings without forgetting anything?
君から聞きたいよ 何回目の僕に出会った?
I want to hear it from you—how many times have you met me?
僕は変わりました 新しい君に出会うために
I have changed, in order to meet a new you.
久しぶりだねって 言えたならここで泣きそうかっ
If I could say "It's been a while," I'd probably cry right here.
好きとかって 嫌いとかって 何度だって愛を歌う君が
You, who sing of love over and over, saying "I like you" or "I hate you,"
恋しくって 嘘じゃない本当だよ また出会おう
I miss you, and it's no lie, it's the truth—let's meet again.
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って 何回だって間違ってきたよ
We hated "II", went back to "I", and made mistakes countless times.
消えない後悔と 冷めない愛情が 恋を再起動する
Unfading regrets and unwavering affection reboot our romance.
ほら“I”を嫌ってまた“II”に戻って “III”になって愛を繋いでいこう
Look, let's hate "I", go back to "II", become "III", and keep connecting our love.
言いたい感情は 伝えたい正解は
The feelings I want to express, the correct answer I want to convey,
想いの冒険は これからもちゃんと続いていく
and the adventure of our feelings will properly continue from now on.
3と9に乗って 言葉とか飛び越えちゃって
Riding on 3 and 9, leaping right past words and all,
君も変わりました 新しい誰かに会うために
you too have changed, in order to meet someone new.
大人になりました それだけでいいと思えた
I became an adult, and I felt that alone was enough.
好きとかって 嫌いとかって 何度だって愛を歌う君が
You, who sing of love over and over, saying "I like you" or "I hate you,"
恋しくって 嘘じゃない本当だよ また出会おう
I miss you, and it's no lie, it's the truth—let's meet again.
恋をして バカ… 愛にして バカ…
Falling in love, idiot... Turning it into love, idiot...
バカでいい この先もずっとこのままバカ…
Idiotic is fine, staying just like this forever... idiot...
バカでいい この先もずっとこのまま
Stupid is fine, let's stay just like this forever...
僕ら“II”を嫌って“I”に戻って
Wishing on "II" and returning to "I",
何回だって 間違って来たよ
How many times have I made this mistake?
消えない後悔と 冷めない感情が恋を再起動する
Unfading regrets and lingering passion reignite our love.
ほら“I”を嫌って また“II”に戻って“III”になって 愛を繋いでいこう
Moving from "I" to "II", then to "III", let's connect our love.
言いたい感情は 伝えたい正解はたったひとつだけ
The feelings I want to say, the truths I want to convey are just one.
ありがとう
Thank you!
メーデー 僕と判っても
Mayday, if you find out it's me...
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ もっとちゃんと不安にしてよ
You don't need to hold me tight, just make me anxious.
愛を懐いて理想を号んだ
Embracing love and shouting ideals.
行き場のある愛のメロディーを
Singing a homeless love melody.
これまでにありがとう いつまでも君と
Thank you for everything up until now, and forever with you.
「こんな歌あったね」って 出会い数を数えられるように
So we can count all our meetings as "We had songs like that."